(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T20:26:43.217728",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
base instincts take control
like primal ways of a warrior
is it glory you're after, like me?
underestimated everywhere I turn
taking aim but it doesn't make a difference at all
I got a million different enemies I cannot recall
you're rocking up to a battle when you know that you'll fall
hidden motivation, watch it all burn
I gotta tell you
I never liked you
now would I lie to you?
let me ignite you
when thunder crashes down
when the world caves under my pressure
there'll be no one to save
where is your pride, your human will to survive?
was it just
empty words for your grave?
I reach inside this soul
now all that remains
is delusion and decay
'cuz of you, I live this way
we're not rivals
we're not equals
you're just confused
lightning never strikes twice in the same spot
so go ahead and run up on me till you get your shot
I see the weapon that you're hiding, come on ready or not
another life and you would never give a second thought
thinkin' your pride's different than mine
ticking all your vital signs off
but we still gotta
protect all our friends from our enemies
wouldn't you agree?
forged in fires of hell
god can't betray you
if I'm a fallen angel
what does that make you?
I'm not debasing myself
to see the same view
when it's your pride on the line
no one can save you from mine
we're not rivals
we're not equals
and it never strikes twice in the same spot
so go ahead and run up on me so you get your shot
a hidden weapon that you're hiding, come on ready or not
another life and you would never give a second thought
thinkin' your pride's different than mine
ticking all your vital signs off
but we still gotta protect all our friends from our enemies
wouldn't you agree?
forged in fires of hell, god can't betray you
if i'm a fallen angel, what does that make you?
i'm not debasing myself to see the same view
when it's your pride on the line, no one can save you from mine
we're not rivals!
we're not equals!
Hello minasan!
Hello everyone!
Yeah yeah! Whoa, this is...
Well then, thank you.
This is Mori Calliope. Yorikariope desu.
Thank you so much everybody for coming to my birthday live!
Here's the hashtag #UncutRock right here, right here, right here.
Check it out everybody.
Today's theme is obviously birthday, right? It's my birthday.
And so, if you look behind us, we've got stones!
Oh my gosh, what kind of stones I wonder? Maybe birthday stones, depending on the guest I suppose. Well, Mori Calliope is diamond.
So, of course, you will see white behind me, yes.
And the idea is to sing original songs with guests, and also my own songs, and I'm looking at the comments right now.
Now, the show isn't very high quality, so there's like a pretty big lag, but I'm looking, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Holy canoli!
Holy cannoli!
Holy cannoli is right. Kombawa, kombawa.
Holy cannoli is right. Konbanwa, konbanwa.
Comment o mitemasu.
I'm reading the comments.
Whoa, sugoi! Happy birthday, happy birthday! Happy birthday wish, arigatou gozaimasu.
Whoa, amazing! Happy birthday, happy birthday! Happy birthday wishes, arigatou gozaimasu.
And you know what, behind me is not only stones, but I also have a fabulous band joining me! Yes, that's right, live band!
Thank you so much to the band for coming. Now, in particular, we have somebody that Calliope and me really respect.
Today, Park-san is here with us!
Kari-chan, happy birthday!
Thank you!
Yoroshiku onegaishimasu.
Yeah, Park-san is one of my favorite bass players ever. He's done two songs for me, in particular, Orpheus and Sepia. Orpheus to Sepia no besu yatte kuremashita. Park-san wa sugoi risupekuto shitemasu.
Hai! But I have so many wonderful members in the band today, and also guests as well. I don't want to take up too much more time, but anyway, we should probably sing with guests because I want to showcase all that we've been practicing together. So, let's go ahead and begin... the first guest. Come on!
閉ざした世界
In a closed-off world,
かすかに聞こえる音
I can faintly hear it.
世界で二人きりみたいだ
Feels like it's just the two of us here.
届きそうな手
Hands almost touch,
すれ違った心が
But our hearts drift apart,
ちょっと痛むんだ
And it hurts just a bit.
ここで待って　ここで待って　ここで待って
(Wait for me here, wait for me here, wait for me here)
決められないままで
I'm stuck in uncertainty,
戸惑いあふれてしまうよ
Hesitating, too much confusion spilling out.
もう何度も繰り返した
Repeating again and again,
こぼれた想いを数えて
counting up the feelings that spilled over,
何度も繰り返した
repeating again and again,
世界　世界　開くのを待っている
waiting for the world, the world to open up.
壊した世界
In this broken world,
回り続ける針は
the hands keep spinning,
ちぎれた意識繋いでいく
connecting frayed consciousness,
歪んだ金属音
the distorted metallic sound
鳴り響く心に
resonates in my heart,
ちょっと響くんだ
hitting it just a little.
ここで待って　ここで待って　ここで待って
(Wait for me here, wait for me here, wait for me here)
君を僕と繋げないまま
unable to connect you and me.
Oh… 死んでしまうとは情けない！
Oh... It's pathetic to just die like that!
三、二、一、oh!
Three, two, one, oh!
「王！」「何？」
"King!" "What?"
「Help！」「何事じゃ」
"Help!" "What's wrong?"
「ひっ、姫がさらわれましたぁ」
"Ah, the princess was kidnapped!"
「勇者は？」「いません」
"The hero?" "None."
「うーん、そうだ！おまえが勇者だ」
"Then you shall be the hero!"
さぁ、その宝箱の中身とこの金で旅立って…
"Take that treasure chest and this money to set off..."
何度も繰り返した 世界、世界、
Repeated over and over, the world, the world...
悲鳴の中を舞える
Dancing amidst the screams!
もう何にもいらないから
I don't need anything anymore,
心の中を纏おろし
So shroud your inner thoughts...
何度も繰り返した 世界、世界、悲鳴の中を…
Repeating over and over, world, world, amidst screams...
もう何度も繰り返した 神様に願いをかけて
Repeating over and over, praying to God...
何度も繰り返した 世界、世界、悲鳴の中で疼く
Repeating over and over, world, world, throbbing in screams.
イェイ！イェイ！
Yay! Yay!
Our first guest is あずき先輩！
Our first guest is AZKi-senpai!
あずき、右手にマイク、左手にチーズ、あなたのハートをゼロゲットー！
AZKi, mic in right hand, cheese in left, zero-getting your heart!
かりおぺちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calliope-chan, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！バースデーです！誕生日です！
Thank you so much! It's my birthday!
誕生日かぁ、おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
さっき一緒に歌った曲大好きです！
I love the song we sang together just now!
なんとAZKiのオリジナル曲を一緒に歌わせていただきました！
And we got to sing one of AZKi's original songs together!
そうですね、ずっとバンドアレンジで歌いたかったから
Yeah, I've always wanted to sing it with a full band arrangement,
歌いたかったから選びました。めちゃ熱かったです！
so I chose it. It was super passionate!
楽しかったよね、バンドの演奏もすごく格好良かったです！
It was so fun, and the band's performance was so cool!
ちなみに、ステージも見てほしい
By the way, check out the stage too!
いや、すごい！めちゃくちゃピカピカ光ってる！ピカピカストーン、ピカピカストーン…めっちゃ素敵ですね！
It's amazing, sparkling so much! Sparkling stones, sparkling stones... It's so lovely!
ちなみに、AZKi先輩の誕生座席は…AZKiの誕生石は7月なんですけど
By the way, AZKi-senpai's birthstone... well, my birthstone is July,
ルビー！ルビーこの色、になりました！
Ruby! Ruby became this color!
すごい！今日の色が変わるんですね、今日は！すごい、めっちゃ赤です！そうですね、綺麗！
Amazing! Today's colors change! It's super red! So pretty!
めっちゃ綺麗から一緒に、なんか、あの写真撮りたい…
Since it's so pretty, let's take a photo together...
せっかく、テスクリンショット！スクリーンショット！
Let's take screenshots! Screenshots!
いい感じです！イェイ！
Looking good! Yay!
じゃあ、生ライブだからやっぱ、水飲みたいと思う。水飲もう！
Well, since it's a live stream, I want to drink water. Let's drink water!
乾杯！水乾杯でーす！乾杯！
Cheers! A water cheers! Cheers!
チアーズ！乾杯！
Cheers! Cheers!
じゃあ、次の曲！お、次の曲はなんだっけな？一曲ありますよね、一緒に。
Now, the next song! What's the next song? We have a song together.
あります！そう、さっきAZKi先輩の曲を歌いましたね。今回はカリオペのオリジナル曲です！
Yes! We sang AZKi-senpai's song earlier. This time it's Calliope's original song!
ネクストソングはカリオペのオリジナル「未来島」！
The next song is Calliope's original, "Future Island"!
未来島 -Future Island-
[Title: 未来島 -Future Island-]
危険な海に浮かぶ島 エッグヘッド
Egghead, an island floating on a dangerous sea
世界変える未来島のラボフェーズ
Lab phase of Future Island that changes the world
最高の脳髄 叶えるよ 願望
The highest intellect, making wishes come true
未来のお宝 探しちゃお
Let's go search for the future treasure!
天才が引き起こす発想の奇跡
A miracle of inspiration sparked by a genius
脳内で終わらせない夢のファンタジー
A fantasy of dreams that doesn't end in the brain
世界がひっくり返るテクノロジー
Technology that turns the world upside down
大体叶えちゃうラボラトリー
A laboratory that makes almost anything come true
シャカ リリス エディソン ピタゴラス アトラス ヨーク 6人のサテライト
Shaka, Lilith, Edison, Pythagoras, Atlas, York, six satellites
湧き出すアイデア止まらない 忙しすぎて猫の手も借りたい
Ideas keep gushing out, so busy I could use a helping hand
海も波も超えてゆく海賊王 常識変えてゆく発明王
The Pirate King crossing seas and waves, the Invention King changing common sense
そんな奴らに憧れてきた 次は誰が王になる？
Admiring such people, who will be next on the throne?
無限の夢 未来の知恵 ひらめきを巻き起こせ エッグヘッド
Infinite dreams, wisdom of the future, stir up inspiration, Egghead!
無限の夢 未来の知恵 過去も世界も飛び越して ベガパンク
Infinite dreams, future wisdom, transcending past and world, Vegapunk!
生み出すよアイデア ベガパンク ベガパンク
Creating ideas, Vegapunk, Vegapunk!
革命をここから ベガパンク
Revolution starting right here, Vegapunk!
危険な海に浮かぶ島 エッグヘッド 世界変える未来島のラボフェーズ
Egghead, an island floating on a dangerous sea, lab phase of Future Island that changes the world
危険な海に浮かぶ島へ
To an island floating on a dangerous sea,
世界変える未来島の手前へ
Before the future island that will change the world,
Let's Head!
This mind is undefeated,
And still my goal's completed.
Let's keep on searching for the treasure yet to come!
Genius, a miracle, a diva, gotta set it straight!
Fantastic dreams are burning up inside of me!
We'll lead, we'll turn the world around with new technology!
Feel on, elaborate story cast upon the sea!
Navigate into evil and the contents of mind, right into knowledge greeting by lunar 6 satellites!
Ideas can't stop flushing out, stop thinking they might, could use a hand to busy working into the night!
The pirate king o'erwaves the ocean while in search of elation,
A ruler of invention that can modify your reason!
Once washed in jealousy, someday I've got to be...
Fixed on the throne, I know what I've got to do!
目覚めの夢　未来の知恵　知られざる記憶を巻き起こせ　Let's Head!
A waking dream, future wisdom, stir up unknown memories—Let's Head!
目覚めの夢　未来の知恵　過去の世界も飛び越して　Let's Head!
A waking dream, future wisdom, leaping over past worlds—Let's Head!
海の底よ　アイディア　Let's Head!
To the bottom of the sea, ideas—Let's Head!
革命をここから　Let's Head!
Revolution from right here—Let's Head!
海の底よ　アイディア　Let's Head!
To the bottom of the sea, ideas—Let's Head!
おきっときって　笑いだけど　冗談なら笑えないよ
You act all tough and laugh it off, but I can't laugh at that as a joke.
中途半端　どっち付かずの　新境地に手を伸ばした
Halfway, non-committal, I reached out toward a new frontier.
秘密の夜は　夢物語　その光は皆無視して
The secret night is a fantasy, ignoring all of that light entirely.
さあ湧く鼓動　まで聞かないで　幻じゃヤダよ
Come on, don't even listen to the surging heartbeat—I hate illusions!
私を奪って　無数の弾道　千ナイフ　広がって収まらないハート
Steal me away! Countless trajectories, a thousand knives, a spreading, uncontrollable heart!
君の表情は　私の新場所を　書き換えるかも知れない将来ね
Your expression might just rewrite my new place in the future, right?
いざごさいだん　(Dance dance dance) we are dancingly　十二の色彩を　ゼログラビティ
Now, step up to the altar (Dance dance dance) we are dancingly, coloring it with twelve hues in zero gravity!
山はすう　(Dance dance dance) just a dance just a dance 声は闇に預けたまま
Mountain haze (Dance dance dance) just a dance, just a dance, leaving my voice entrusted to the darkness.
目覚めの夢　離れないで
Waking dream, don't leave me.
未来みたいにただよえば　雲も曇もなかった
If I drifted like the future, there were no clouds or gloom.
だれかこれそんなじゃないから　一人じめしてゆっくりや
Someone... it's not like that, so hog it all to yourself slowly.
消してないよ　話そう食って　命のようには流せない
I haven't erased it, let's talk and eat, it can't flow away like life.
寂しく　毒々しい偽りだって　隠しきれない増長にな
Lonely and garish falsehoods, an inability to hide my arrogance.
私に構って　嬉しいなんて Crazy crazy love　までのからすれさっかて
Pay attention to me, saying "I'm so happy" — crazy crazy love, until we get left behind.
君の表情は　私の新心理を　書き換えるかも知れない将来ね
Your expression might rewrite my inner psychology for the future, right?
過ぎ去ったねおんざんとろ　しゅりすの
The neon stone that has passed...
未来みたいにただよえば　雲も曇もなかった
If I drifted like the future, there were no clouds or gloom.
指先でまた　君を探している　その声を聞かせてよ
With my fingertips once more, I am searching for you—let me hear your voice!
私に構って
Pay attention to me,
教えてよ 声の先を
tell me where the voice leads.
広がって おさまんない vibes
Spreading out, uncontainable vibes.
君の存在は
Your existence is
私の想定外までも 踏み込んだなら 突き合ってよ ねぇ
stepping past my expectations, so keep up with me, okay?
痛い 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛い
Painful, painful, painful, painful, painful, painful,
隙間だらけの日々で転び逢った 泥まみれ
immersed in a gap-filled routine, we collided and got muddy.
Gimme boss, dance, dance, dance, just a dance, just a dance
声は闇に足蹴とばして 目を覚ましても
kicking the voice into the darkness, even when I wake up,
離れないで
don't leave me.
Yes, our second guest is Sora-senpai!
はーい！みんなかさぶた剥きなさいよ！借りちゃう！Happy birthday!
Hi everyone, rip off those scabs! Borrowing it! Happy birthday!
Thank you!
そら大先輩！今日誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-senpai, happy birthday today!
ずっと一緒に歌いたかったから…
Thank you so much for wanting to sing together...
あ、本当ですか？ありがとうございます！
Oh really? Thank you!
嬉しいですよマジで！やった！
I'm seriously so happy! Yay!
Hey hey hey!
かわいいよね！
So cute, right?
すごいして、すごいたくさん踊りました！
And we danced so much!
あ、本当だったね！
Ah, that's true!
アイドルわお！ドキドキ！
Idol wow! So thrilling!
ドキドキ？
Thrilling?
Yes! Oh oh!
てかかり、エクスプレス
By the way, Xpress...
X trending number 3! X trend in Japan!
Congratulations!
みんなのフレンドやった！やった！
Everyone, we did it! Yay!
ありがとう！たくさん使ってね！Please hashtag! Thank you so much!
Thank you! Please use it a lot! Please hashtag! Thank you so much!
あ、私すごく幸せ！ありがとう！Yay!
Ah, I'm so happy! Thank you! Yay!
そしてなんか今回 大好きな曲一緒に歌いました！
And we sang one of our favorite songs together!
1,000 Glee!
すごいなんかparty happy! ですよね、大好きです。
It's super party happy, right? I love it.
Danceable!
めっちゃよかった！ありがとう！
It was so good! Thank you!
そしてほら、エメラルド来た！
And look, Emerald came!
ねぇ、綺麗緑！エメラルドですよね！誕生日一番星ですよね！
Hey, gorgeous green! It's Emerald! Birthday's brightest star, right?
そう、5月の誕生日石エメラルドです！
Yes, May's birthstone is Emerald!
Emerald! Wow!
すごい良い発音！ナイスイングリッシュ！
Such great pronunciation! Nice English!
そうですよね。
That's right.
ちなみに写真撮ろっか？あ、撮る！
By the way, shall we take a picture? Ah, let's do it!
Let's do it!
いいっすね！イエーイ！
Nice! Yay!
いいっすね！イエーイ！この写真もアップしてね！X！
Nice! Yay! Upload this picture too! X!
よろしくね！よろしくお願いします！
Please take care of us!
楽しい！じゃあ水飲みましょ！
So fun! Then let's drink some water!
水！いいんですか？
Water! Is that okay?
乾杯！乾杯！
Cheers! Cheers!
飲んだほうがいいっすよね！
You should drink up, right?
そうね、水は大事。
That's right, water is important.
そうだよ！あー楽しい生ライブ！
That's right! Ah, fun live stream!
もう1曲一緒に歌いたいんですけど、大丈夫ですか？
I want to sing another song together, is that okay?
もちろん！Let's do it, okay?
Of course! Let's do it, okay?
Now, everyone please listen to this next song... Please enjoy my オリジナル曲 "Dawn Blue".
Now, everyone please listen to this next song... Please enjoy my original song "Dawn Blue".
Dawn Blue
捕まえて ほら この瞬間を
Catch it, look, this moment,
世界の愛情を集めて
gathering the world's affection.
ずっと 同じ毎日迷いがあっても
Always wandering through the same daily routine,
気づかないフリをしていたんだ
but pretending not to notice.
あの ソットの夢が まだ出せなくて
That gentle dream still can't be expressed,
迷い虫をで さ迷っていた
wandering like a lost insect.
夜空に浮かぶ 星に願いをかけるんだ
I cast a wish upon the stars floating in the night sky.
I hope 抱いている夢を
I hope the dream I hold
絶対諦めたくない
I never want to give up,
走り出すから 追いかけて今 あの瞬間を
because I'm starting to run, so chase after this moment now.
見たことのないストーリー 進んでいくんだ
Advancing into a story I've never seen before,
水の日にきっと 描いた世界へ
surely towards the world we depicted on the day of water.
描いた世界へ 辿り着けるように
so that we can reach the world we depicted.
Got those tastes who thought matter
This is the world we noble
or the dream we sought so long?
つかまえて、ほら
Catch me, look,
このshooting star
this shooting star
ずっと同じ毎日に迷いがあっても
Even if I've been lost in the same everyday life,
気づかないふりをしてたんだ
I was pretending not to notice.
ほんのちょっとの勇気がまだ出せなくて
I still couldn't find just a little bit of courage,
It takes something to believe the wish we were promised could really come to life
And so, if this is how the story goes to find that strength inside...
I'll remember why back then you took my hand, and you said...
Catch me, look, this shooting star
Come, first let's take a step forward
ざまあみろほらこのshout it out
Take that, look, this shout it out
さあまずは一歩踏み出して恐れずにゆこうも
Come on, first take a step forward and go without fear
いつ日の日にきっとまだ見ぬ世界へ辿り着けるように
So that someday I can surely reach a world I've never seen
弱気に咲いた月が
The moon that bloomed timidly
瞬く間にブルーの空に溶けてく
melts into the blue sky in the blink of an eye
You and I, an undecided future, doesn't matter if the final truth hurts
もうすぐ朝が動き出すから
Because morning is about to start moving soon,
抱きしめて今このshooting star
embrace it now, this shooting star,
見たことのないストーリー
a story I've never seen
I'll be here betting on that fearsome heart 'cause you're that shooting star
It's hopeless now, but maybe if you take that step into the darkness you'll find me
Running by your side until the dawn hear me out if you and me us against tomorrow
Face the world that we had dreamed dry your eyes and don't look back
Thank you so much Sora-senpai, mata isshoni utaimashou!
Thank you so much, Sora-senpai! Let's sing together again!
Arigatou! Bye-bye! Matane!
Thank you! Bye-bye! See you later!
See you! Waa, tanoshii ne namaraibu!
See you! Wow, live shows are so much fun!
Oh man, this is so fun! I just love singing. I love singing live so much and you guys, thank you for being a part of it. Woo!
Nailed it, you think so? Because Sora-senpai was by my side. It was awesome.
Now next, I'll be singing with a surprise secret guest, but it's a bit of a break for myself and the band right now because we're going to go back in time...
to a time when I recorded something with a special guest... So please enjoy that special guest performance and I'll see you guys soon!
偶然そこに落ちたんだけどきっと不幸に落ちたんだ
By chance I fell right there, but surely I fell into misfortune.
気づけば僕らは恋を呼んでいた あなたの作恋によるものだったんだ見事さ
Before I knew it, we were calling it love. It was by your design, how brilliant.
地獄の片道切符 理性を奪うリップ
A one-way ticket to hell, lips that steal away reason.
妄想 高揚 本能 暴走 so mellow
Delusion, exaltation, instinct running wild, so mellow.
さながら脳に数枚のチップ 埋め込むような狂愛のキス
Like a few chips embedded in the brain, a kiss of mad love.
「アシタ アナタの永久にVIP」 囁いた言葉 ずっと離れずに あなたに あなたに あなたに
"I am your eternal VIP." The words whispered never left me—to you, to you, to you...
相応しいヒトになれますか
Can I become someone fitting?
ああ、あ、あ、あ、あ、あ、あ
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
Right you left me 愛す you So we did it did it did it did it stop
Right you left me, I love you. So we did it, did it, did it, did it, stop.
I love you my girl I love you my boy あなたを知って 全ては過去になる
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. Knowing you, everything becomes the past.
I love you my girl I love you my boy 幸せに満ちた 未来を作ろうね そう 愛し切って どうかこんな僕を 愛し切って どうかこんなアシタを
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. Let's create a future filled with happiness. Yeah, love me to the end, please, someone like me. Love me to the end, please, someone like me.
Give me give me give me give me love
ねえ アシタに退屈を着せないで とびきりのドレスとあなたのエスコートで
Hey, don't clothe me in boredom, with an exquisite dress and your escort.
赤く染まる絨毯の上 歩く ママじゃないけどアシタはスター
I walk upon the carpet dyed red. I'm not a pit viper, but I am a star.
口移し 流し込む 罪の味 共犯ね これであなたは アシタに アシタに アシタに
The taste of sin poured mouth-to-mouth. We're accomplices now—with this, you—to me, to me, to me...
相応しいヒトになりました Right you left me 愛す you So we did it did it did it did it stop
Have become someone fitting. Right you left me, I love you. So we did it, did it, did it, did it, stop.
I love you my girl I love you my boy 裏表 あなた 僕 罪と蜜
I love you my girl, I love you my boy. Front and back, you and me, sin and honey.
3, 2, 1
だって安全無事だけじゃ物足りない
Just living safely and uneventfully isn't enough.
しょっぱいアイス ペラのお菓子 口うつし流し込む 罪の味
Salty ice cream, flimsy sweets, passed mouth-to-mouth—the taste of sin.
今日あンね これであなたは
Today, see? With this, you...
私に 私に 私に
...became someone tied down to me, me, me...
捕まり 首輪つけられ 人になりました
collared and made into my person.
Ahh...
Right here, left me, I see you
So we did it, did it, did it, did it, stop.
I love you, you're my girl
I love you, you're my boy
裏表持って あなた僕と罪見つめ
With two sides, you and I looked at our sins.
I love you, you're my girl
I love you, you're my boy
その味する前には戻れない
I can't go back to before I knew that taste.
そう愛して見せて どうかっこんな僕を
So show me your love, please, for someone like me—
愛して見せて どうかっこんな私を
show me your love, please, for someone like me—
君君君君君だ
It's you, you, you, you, you!
皆さん、ようこそ。周防さん＆カリオペ 3Dバースデーライブ！
Welcome, everyone! Shudo & Calliope's 3D Birthday Live!
Thank you!
狂い合うように 癒し合うように
As if driving each other mad, as if healing each other,
求め合ってしまうのよ
we end up craving one another—
予想ができないじゃん
who could have ever expected this?
与えられた天国より 選んだ地獄を
Choosing the hell we picked over the heaven we were given,
あなたと二人なら 堕ちるまで
if it's the two of us, until we fall into the abyss.
I love you, you're my girl
I love you, you're my boy
確かめていく
Confirming it as we go.
I love you, you're my girl
I love you, you're my boy
あなたを知って 全ては過去になる
Knowing you, everything becomes the past.
I love you, you're my girl
I love you, you're my boy
疾走するに満ちた未来 作ろうぜ
Let's create a future overflowing with momentum.
そう愛し切って どうかっこんな僕を
So love me to the fullest, please, for someone like me—
愛し切って どうかっこんな私を
love me to the fullest, please, for someone like me—
そう愛し合ってしまったこんな僕ら
the two of us who ended up loving each other like this,
果てまでにはかりを告げて
announcing the measure right up to the end.
君君君君君ら
You, you, you, you, you!
あは、皆さん、どうお思いましでしょうか？
Ah, everyone, what did you think?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
楽しかったー！
That was so fun!
イエイイエイイエイ！スペシャルゲスト、周野さんが来ましたー！
Yay, yay, yay! Special guest Shudo-san has arrived!
こんにちは！
Hello!
VTuberの皆さん、こんにちは、周野です。
Hello everyone on VTuber, I'm Shudo.
イエス！自己紹介お願いします！
Yes! Please introduce yourself!
はい、えー僕はですね、ミュージシャンやってます、周野でございます。そして
Yes, um, I'm Shudo, a musician. And...
ハッピーバースデー、カリオペさん！おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday, Calliope-san! Congratulations!
ライブも最高です！
The live performance is amazing too!
あ、ちなみにハイタッチしたい、いいですか？
Oh, by the way, I'd like a high-five. Is that okay?
あ、行きますか？いきますか？
Oh, shall we do it? Shall we?
はい、せーの！ハイタッチ！えー！
Okay, ready, go! High five! Yay!
いい感じ！ありがとうございます！
Feels great! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
イエイ！
Yay!
ちなみに周野さんは、音楽活動いろいろやってますね。ね、どんな活動やってますか？
By the way, Shudo-san, you do various musical activities, right? What kind of activities do you do?
そうですね、僕はあのボカロPですね。ボカロPとして楽曲を作ったり、シンガーソングライターとして歌を歌いさせていただいたり、そしていろんな方に楽曲を提供したり、え、そんな活動をさせていただいております。
Well, I'm a Vocaloid producer, creating songs, singing as a singer-songwriter, and providing songs to others.
いやもうもちろん私知ってるけど、大ファンだからね！嬉しい、そのライブも以前来ていただきまして。
Of course I know you, I'm a huge fan! I'm so happy you came to my live before.
そうですね、武道館ライブめちゃ楽しかった！いや、ありがとうございます。本当僕も楽しくて、めちゃくちゃ盛り上がったんで、はい、嬉しいです、今日出られて。はい。
That's right, the Budokan live was super fun! Thank you, I had a blast and it got so hype, I'm so glad I could be here today.
こちらこそ私もすごい嬉しいですね。ありがとうございます。このステージ、どう思いますか？
Likewise, I'm super happy too. Thank you. What do you think of this stage?
いやこれすごいですよね、後ろからこの高さも含めて。僕ちょっと高いところ苦手なんんで、落ちないように気をつけながらやらないとなと思うんですけども、最高です、これ。はい。
This is amazing, from the back to this height. I'm a bit bad with high places, so I have to be careful not to fall, but it's the best!
かなり高いけど、気をつけてね！確かに下見えないからね、やべえ。
It's pretty high, so be careful! True, you can't see the bottom, yikes.
はい。え、でも、そういえば、なんかテーマが誕生日だから、あの、ちょっと知りたいね、周野さんの誕生日はいつですか？
Right. Oh, but since the theme is birthdays, when is your birthday, Shudo-san?
僕の誕生日9月です。
My birthday is in September.
セプテンバー！
September!
セプテンバーです。
It's September.
ああ、セプテンバーのバースデーストーン、誕生日ストーンはサファイアです。
Ah, September's birthstone is sapphire.
サファイアです。
Sapphire.
もうほら、ステージはサファイア、あ、サファイア、サファイア！
Look, the stage is sapphire, sapphire, sapphire!
どういうことだったんだこれ。僕に合わせてくれた？ありがとうございます。たまたまですけど、あの、服もこの青で、星も青であってんだで、うわ相性がいい！めっちゃ嬉しい、そうですね。ありがとうございます。
What does this mean? Did you match it to me? It's a coincidence, but my clothes and stars were blue too, great compatibility!
すごい、めっちゃいい感じですね。いいですね、嬉しいですね。わあ、え、次の曲は、周野さんが書き下ろしてくれたやつですね。
Amazing, it feels really good. The next song is the one Shudo-san wrote for us, right?
そうですね。あの、僕がすごくカリオペさんのもちろん楽曲大好きなんですけども、カリオペさんのこう、かっこよくて、あの、強くって、すごい美しいみたいなところを引き出せるような楽曲として作らせていただいた、え、曲でございますね。
That's right. I made it as a song that brings out parts of Calliope-san like being cool, strong, and beautiful.
いや、とうや、めっちゃいい曲、本当に、なんかすっごい大好きな曲だから。
Such a great song, really, it's a song I love so much.
あ、嬉しい、ありがとうございます。マジで本当に感謝してます。
Ah, I'm glad, thank you. I honestly really appreciate it.
ありがとうございます。今回一緒に歌いたいと思います。
Thank you. I want to sing it together this time.
初めてですね、一緒に歌うのはこれはね。
It's our first time singing together.
初めてです。
It's our first time.
レアなではないでしょうか。大丈夫ですか？
Isn't it rare? Are you okay?
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
オケー！じゃあ次の曲に行く前に、みんなに伝えたいことありますか？
Okay! Before moving to the next song, do you have anything you want to tell everyone?
Shido-san, yonde kurete arigatou gozaimasu!
Shido-san, thank you for inviting me!
Iya iya, kochira koso.
No, no, the pleasure is mine.
Ja aa, sore de kiite kudasai ne.
Well then, please listen to this.
Demo, Shido-san, shoukai shite kudasai!
But Shido-san, please introduce it!
Soredewa o-kiki kudasai, LET'S JUST CRASH.
Now then, please listen: LET'S JUST CRASH.
Hey, hey, minasan!
Hey, hey, everyone!
Let's go!
Hey, hey! Let's go!
You got eyes and ears, but you don't look or listen
In other words, you're useless, every last one of ya
And that's why I'm gonna send you all to hell! All of humanity! Hell!
Seien seoi sassou to toujou
I stride in, bearing the cheers,
Soui un janee
that's not it.
I'm just the type you'd forget
So don't waste your time
Yeah, a chain that's torn and rotting, going insane
Somebody's gotta pay while I live with the pain
Look at me now
I'm the one you can't tame, hah!
Teizokude saitei no tensai soui un de ii
A vulgar, lowest-of-the-low genius—will that do?
Omoi ga tsunoru basho ni hana wa saku kara
Flowers bloom where longing gathers.
Let's riot
Get back, you're trash
hakidame de kibou wo
hope in the garbage dump.
Let's just crash
tsumiagete iku nda
we'll keep piling it up.
Itadaki kara takaraka ni warae
Laugh loudly from the summit!
Lose control
utsukushiki risou wo
over the beautiful ideal!
Heads will roll
yogo shitekuru yarou wa
the bastard who'll dirty it—
Dare da ittai? Dare da ittai?
who the hell is it? Who is it?
Dare datta toshite mo
Whoever it was...
Kono risou wa muridaro tte
You'd say this ideal is impossible,
Dare ga itta toshite mo kanaete kouze
whoever said it, let's make it come true.
Seikai fu seikai no kaitou dou datte ii
The right or the wrong answer doesn't matter,
Sonna tokku no touni koeta basho ni ore wa tatteiru
I'm standing in a place I've long since surpassed.
Yeah, meaningless problems
Everybody's got 'em and they can't be satisfied
Until somebody's at the bottom, so what?
You think you're special 'cause you got some grit and hunger?
We ain't getting any younger, thinking let's just crash
Kokoro ga kayou toki ni tamashi ga sakebu
When hearts commune, souls cry out!
Get back, you're trash
dobunezumi no yoo ni
like a sewer rat.
Let's just crash
kedakaku ikiru nda
live nobly!
Ore ga touru ima sugu ni doke
Clear the way right now where I pass!
Let's riot
Get back, you're trash
hakidame de kibou wo
hope in the garbage dump.
Let's just crash
tsumiagete iku nda
we'll keep piling it up.
Itadaki kara takaraka ni warae
Laugh loudly from the summit!
Lose control
utsukushiki risou wo
over the beautiful ideal!
Heads will roll
yogo shitekuru yarou wa
the bastard who'll dirty it—
Dare da ittai? Dare da ittai?
who the hell is it? Who is it?
Dare datta toshite mo
Whoever it was...
Kono risou wa muridaro tte
You'd say this ideal is impossible,
Dare ga itta toshite mo kanaete kouze
whoever said it, let's make it come true.
Hey, hey! Let's go!
Shido-san, arigatou gozaimashita! Thank you, Giga-P!
Shido-san, thank you very much! Thank you, Giga-P!
kanaete kouze
Let's make it come true!
Demo, madamada owattenai-ssu ne, minasan!
But it's not over yet, everyone!
Let's just crash!
Arigatou gozaimasu! Bye-bye, Shido-san! Thank you, Deathbed, and the Giga-P!
Thank you very much! Bye-bye, Shido-san! Thank you, Deathbed, and Giga-P!
Aa minasan, that was so fun!
Ah, everyone, that was so fun!
I really respect Shido-san as an artist, he does a lot of his work, uh, himself for his songs, you know, writes and composes and sings and everything.
I really respect Shido-san as an artist. He does a lot of his work himself for his songs, writes, and composes, and sings, and everything.
He's really cool, so big ups to Shido-san!
But I think it is about time that maybe we get back to the future, the present, where I'm performing with all my friends right now.
Yes! But that was a lot of fun. And uh, as I thought, right on time, it looks like it's time for me to get back to the future and go sing with all my friends again...
Yes! But that was a lot of fun. And as I thought, right on time, it looks like it's time for me to get back to the future and go sing with all my friends again...
Walking an empty road, nowhere for me to go
Lost and lonely, yeah, it’s only me
lost and lonely, yeah, it's only me.
lost and lonely
Yeah, it's only me
burnt out like a candlelight
left blazing through the night
melting slowly
until nothing else is left of me
colored in shades of gray
watching the days
pass in front of me
longing to find a way
I can fly away
and drifting through this blue blue world
It's always been clear to me
how cruel the world can be
my shadow's the only one beside me
no love to call my own
no notice on my phone
sunken in silence
has engulfed the fairy life I lived
colored in shades of gray
watching the years pass in front of me
memories I wish would stay
always fade away
and I'm lonely in this blue blue world
though my heart is torn
and my weary wings are worn
just tonight, can I dream of a better life
with happiness inside?
colored in shades of gray
watching my life pass in front of me
maybe it's not too late
if I can't escape, I'll have to make my own way
colored in shades of gray
painted in head, I can make a change
I'll try to find the sky
take a breath and then bring color to this blue blue world
Wow, beautiful, Nerissa!
You're so great!
Ah, thank you for coming!
That emotional song!
Now we're all energetic!
Oh my god, hi everybody!
Hey, did you do the feel-good song?
Thank you, thank you.
It is my birthday!
But who is this lovely lady
I'm singing with right now?
Who could I be? Hiya darlings!
This is Hololive English Advent's devilish diva,
the one, the only Nerissa Ravencroft!
Here with you today at your birthday party!
Wow, kakkoii!
Wow, so cool!
Arigatou gozaimasu!
Thank you very much!
Wow, you're so awesome, Nerissa!
Arigatou gozaimasu!
Thank you very much!
so much for letting me sing your Shoji Meguro song together with you.
We both have Shoji Meguro...
Yes, we both do.
I'm happy that my first time performing it got to be with you.
Seriously, it was so fun. It's always fun singing with a friend.
Thank you for letting me be a part of it.
You got the harmonies, too!
I did my best to learn the harmonies
and stay consistent. It was amazing. You impressed me.
Thank you so much.
Well, I guess we ought to talk about your birthstone.
Do you know your birthstone's a topaz?
Yes!
It's so pretty. My birthday's November 21st.
I'm a Scorpio, and...
Your little hair clips, so true. My gosh, it just positively lights you up, your glow.
How about we take some pictures in front of the stone?
Yeah, let's do it.
Let's do it. All right, here we go.
Peace, peace, peace.
Don't you demo? Either one's good. Facing each other.
Look a little sexy.
Oh, bow-y.
Meganze, that's very nice.
Meganze, use the hashtag.
Please, please post lots of pictures, okay?
Genta on the drums is the one who played for our original song, Override. Oh, my gosh!
Thank you!
Arigato!
Genta, thank you!
So awesome, really appreciate you. Thank you. So many wonderful band members and guests.
I feel very...
lucky and privileged and lucky to have you here.
Do you want to drink water before we start?
That's a great idea. Let's do that.
Yeah.
Immediately.
Yes.
Omizu and...
Okay. I think we're ready for another song then. How about that?
Let's do it. Okay, together. We can do anything.
Yes.
Please enjoy Orpheus.
I ain’t trying to stress you , I must confess though
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
my heart ’s beating to your song ( oh yeah )
My heart's beating to your song (oh yeah)
thinking hurry up orpheus , time ’s a wasting
Thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
( show me what you really wanna do ! )
(Show me what you really wanna do!)
another late night , aimless dreaming
Another late night, aimless dreaming
the day to day starts to call
still got like a million deadlines
still bleeding red wine
my back up against the wall
i got my headphones on , walk home is long
I got my headphones on, walk home is long
dragging feet like i ’m born to lose
Dragging feet like I'm born to lose
‘ til somehow they ’re tapping along
'Til somehow they're tapping along
to you-know-who ’s song
To you-know-who's song
a melody i can ’t refuse
A melody I can't refuse
i ’m outta line , but it ’s fine , you don ’t know my name
I'm outta line, but it's fine, you don't know my name
safe inside my own mind , i don ’t feel the shame , okay ?
Safe inside my own mind, I don't feel the shame, okay?
i know i get a little carried away
but we got music when there aren ’t any words to say !
But we got music when there aren't any words to say!
cuz in my heart , feel a spark when you look this way
'Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way
gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
now i ’m in distress , you got me possessed , i might be obsessed ,
Now I'm in distress, you got me possessed, I might be obsessed,
so let me get a little something off my chest
look , i ain ’t trying to stress you , i must confess though
Look, I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
my heart ’s beating to your song ( oh yeah )
My heart's beating to your song (oh yeah)
thinking hurry up orpheus , time ’s a wasting
Thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
( show me what you really wanna do ! )
(Show me what you really wanna do!)
tonight , it ’s my turn to show you how obvious i can be
Tonight, it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
sometimes it feels like you ’re playing that guitar for me and only me
Sometimes it feels like you're playing that guitar for me and only me
critics so loud , so predictable , they can ’t see what i can see
Critics so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see
you ’re gonna wind up a star
You're gonna wind up a star
you got me dancing so bizarre
this distance got me feeling fonder , i wonder if it ’s enough
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
cuz i ’m not lying
'Cuz I'm not lying
when i ’m implying you ’re all that i ’ve been thinking of
When I'm implying you're all that I've been thinking of
maybe they ’ll call me delusional
Maybe they'll call me delusional
baby , this could be real love ?
Baby, this could be real love?
give me one chance and i ’ll take
Give me one chance and I'll take
you make me dance the night away
now it ’s a game that i ’ve played before
Now it's a game that I've played before
but with the way the scene changed
there is nothing you can blame me for
i ’m talking tv screens , magazines , seen you in a couple dreams
I'm talking TV screens, magazines, seen you in a couple dreams
pictures up on every padded wall and floor
you ’re always talking ’ bout “ no time to desire a lover ”
You're always talking 'bout “no time to desire a lover”
so , why ’d you paint your nails up in my favorite color ?
So, why'd you paint your nails up in my favorite color?
i got an attitude
just when it comes to you
so yeah reality is kinda slipping out of tune
i ’m never lost in the groove of somebody new
I'm never lost in the groove of somebody new
if it ’s devotion you ’re after , i ’m staying true
If it's devotion you're after, I'm staying true
so are you noticing me noticing you noticing me ?
So are you noticing me noticing you noticing me?
no disillusion but there ’s not a lot of guarantee
No disillusion but there's not a lot of guarantee
cuz in my heart , feel a spark when you look this way
'Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way
gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
you ’re strumming next to me
You're strumming next to me
now i ’m in ecstasy
Now I'm in ecstasy
and for the rest of the week i ’m depression free
And for the rest of the week I'm depression free
i ain ’t trying to stress you , i must confess though
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
my heart ’s beating to your song ( oh yeah )
My heart's beating to your song (oh yeah)
thinking hurry up orpheus , time ’s a wasting
Thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
( show me what you really wanna do ! )
(Show me what you really wanna do!)
tonight , it ’s my turn to show you how obvious i can be
Tonight, it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
so just as long as you keep playing that guitar …
So just as long as you keep playing that guitar...
yeah !
Yeah!
critics so loud , so predictable , they can ’t see what i can see
Critics so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see
you ’re gonna wind up a star ! ! !
You're gonna wind up a star!
Our veins can be golden, taking space with the face of judgment
So let's blow this joint, and if the feelings fight, then we can make a little music out of our oontz at night
Come on! Our veins can be golden, taking space with the face of judgment
Why you walking away? I've got a lot to say, guess I'll save up for the next one
Whoo! I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though, my heart's beating to a song
Oh yeah! So hear me out, Orpheus, I'm thinking next time I'll show you what I really want to do
Bye narcissist! Thanks for singing with me, the rest of her birthday! See ya later! Love you too, bye-bye!
ねえあたしいつも勇気が足りないから 自分を大切にできないんだ
Hey, I never have enough courage, so I can't cherish myself.
痛い目を見ないと気付けやしないんだ ああ今日もキャラメルペインです
I won't realize it unless I learn it the hard way. Ah, it's caramel pain again today.
良い子になんていられないんだって
I just can't be a good girl.
だって世界はこんなにも極彩色で
Because the world is in such vivid colors,
甘ったるくて苦いしああ、って頭痛いし
sweet and bitter, ah, and my head hurts.
ヘトヘトで漂うだけの24/7
Just drifting along exhausted 24/7.
ギリギリ感情抑えるなんてもう無理
Keeping my emotions in check by a thread is impossible now.
このままではいられないの毎日
I can't stay like this every day.
ちょっとこわいけど
It's a bit scary, but...
置いてくよ 置いてくよ 置いてくよ 今までに手に入れたイデオロギーもスタイルも 壊れちゃっても今がいいよ
I'll leave it behind, leave it behind, leave it behind. Even if the ideologies and styles I've gained break, right now is fine.
だってあたしはあたしのままでずっといたいんだもん
Because I just want to stay as I am forever.
ルート？ムード？どうでもいーっしょ トゥーザネクスト
Route? Mood? Whatever! To the next!
もっと危ないことしたら勝ちなんじゃないでしょう
Isn't it about winning if I do something more dangerous?
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
It can't be helped no matter what I sacrifice.
フロムマイベッドこの胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, holding only this pain in my chest,
ああ今日もキャラメルペインです
ah, it's caramel pain again today.
ミルフィーユみたいにはぐらかしたって
Even if I dodge it like a mille-feuille,
いつかバレちゃうよ腐っちゃうよ
it'll get exposed someday, it'll rot away.
痛いとか素直に君に言えてれば
If I had honestly told you it hurts,
今頃何か変わってたのかもね
maybe something would have changed by now.
好きなアニメもなくなっちゃうし
My favorite anime would disappear,
好きな人だってなくなっちゃうんだよ寂しくなっちゃうな
and even the person I love would disappear, how lonely that would be.
大切なことはただ一つだけさ もう後悔しないように 前を向いて生きるということ！
There is only one precious thing: to live looking forward so I won't regret it anymore!
置いてくよ 置いてくよ 置いてくよ 今までに手に入れたイデオロギーもスタイルも 汚れちゃっても気にしないよ
I'll leave it behind, leave it behind, leave it behind. Even if the ideologies and styles I've gained get dirty, I don't care.
だってあたしはあたしに恋してたんだもん
Because I was in love with myself.
愛してるよ 愛してるよ愛してるよ
I love you, I love you, I love you.
さよならなんて涙が出ちゃうけれど
Even though tears fall at a goodbye,
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
it can't be helped no matter what I sacrifice.
置いてくよ置いてくよ置いてくよ 今まで手に入れたイデオロギーもスタイルも
Leave it behind, leave it behind, leave it behind. Ideologies and styles up until now...
汚れてちゃっても気にしないよ
Even if they're stained, I don't care.
だってあたしはあたしに恋してたんだもん
Because I was in love with myself.
愛してるよ愛してるよ愛してるよ
I love you, I love you, I love you.
さよならなんて涙が出ちゃうけれど
Even though tears fall at a goodbye,
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
it can't be helped no matter what I sacrifice.
フロムマイベッドこの胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, holding only this pain in my chest,
ああ今日もキャラメルペインです
ah, it's caramel pain again today.
ねえあたしいつも勇気が足りないから
Hey, I never have enough courage,
自分を大切にできないんだ
so I can't cherish myself.
痛いぐらいなら少し我慢するんだ
If it hurts, I just endure it a little.
ああ今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, it's caramel pain again today.
一緒に出してもらいましてね。
We got to perform together.
懐かしい。
Nostalgic.
ねえ、懐かしい。なんかこんなんもやったっけ？
Yeah, nostalgic. Did we do something like this?
やりました。たくさんやりました。
We did. We did a lot.
やばいよね、めちゃめちゃいい思い出ですよね。わあ。
It's crazy, such great memories, right?
覚えてくれたね、それ。
You remembered that.
ね、久しぶりに歌えて嬉しいね。
Man, it's so nice to sing together after so long.
恥ずかしいポイント。
Embarrassing point.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そうですね、今回キャラメルペイン一緒に歌いました。一番好きな星街スイセイ曲です。
Right, this time we sang "Caramel Pain" together. It's my favorite Hoshimachi Suisei song.
わあ、嬉しい！
Yay, I'm so happy!
やった！めっちゃいい感じだったね、ハモリとかもね。
Yay! It felt so good, including the harmonies.
うん、たくさん練習しました。ねえ、本当綺麗だったぜ。
Yeah, I practiced a lot. Man, it was really pretty.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちなみに、ほら、ピカピカストーン！
By the way, look, sparkly stone!
ワオ、ビューティフル！
Wow, beautiful!
素敵ですよね。そう、てけい、え、スイセイ先輩、あの、後知ってるけど、誕生日はいつですか？
It's lovely. Right, Suisei-senpai, I know you are later, but when is your birthday?
私は3月の22日。March 22!
Mine is March 22nd. March 22!
March 22, March 22. そうですね。
March 22nd, yeah. That's right.
うん、せ、せ、せん、せんが、月、先月、先月。そう、先月。Yes.
Um, last month, last month. Right, last month. Yes.
ですので、ほら、アクアマリンが、誕生、
So, look, Aquamarine is birth-
アクアマリンだ！もうぴったりよね。私知らなかったよ、自分の誕生日好きアクアマリンって。
It's aquamarine! It fits so well. I didn't even know my birth stone was aquamarine.
そう、ぴったりですよ。マジで最高。同じ色だよ。もう同じ色。
Yeah, it fits perfectly. Seriously the best. It's the same color. Already the same color.
最高だぜ。めっちゃ素敵ですよ。ねえ、めっちゃ綺麗だから一緒に写真撮りましょう。
That's awesome. It's super lovely. Hey, since it's so pretty, let's take a photo together.
あ、撮ろう！いいですか？Let's go! Yay!
Ah, let's take one! Ready? Let's go! Yay!
私ね、やりたいものある。えっとね、
I have something I want to do. Uh, let's see,
これ分かる？何のポーズか。No、じゃない。違うよ。What's this?
Do you know what pose this is? No, it's not that. That's wrong. What's this?
ゴールデンベルト！そう。
Golden Belt! That's right.
これめちゃくちゃかっこいいよね。ありがとう。Thank you so much.
This is super cool, right? Thank you. Thank you so much.
え、ちゃんと見てくれてありがとう。もちろん！大好きな曲ですよ。
Thank you so much for watching properly. Of course! It's my favorite song.
Thank you so much, senpai. え,ちなみに、Everybody really quick before we keep going. お知らせあります。Yes。
Thank you so much, senpai. Um, by the way, everybody really quick before we keep going. We have an announcement. Yes.
Quick announcement about members only. メンバーズ限定アンコールがありますよ。ソロセッション。We need to pick one song that I just performed with the amazing guest. And I'm going to do a solo version of it.
Quick announcement about members only. There's a members-only encore! A solo session. We need to pick one song that I just performed with the amazing guest. And I'm going to do a solo version of it.
Yes. So you have 1 minute, starting now! 1分ありますよ、Vote! あのカリオペはソロで歌いますよ。さっきゲストと一緒に歌った曲、Please vote! Everybody, you have 1 minute, go!
Yes. So you have 1 minute, starting now! You have 1 minute, vote! Calliope will sing solo. The song I just sang with the guest earlier, please vote! Everybody, you have 1 minute, go!
この後のメンゲンでソロで歌ってくれるらしいですよ。Yes。
I heard you'll sing it solo in the upcoming members-only stream. Yes.
え、全部聴きたいよ！そうだね。全部めちゃめちゃいい曲、全てのが。やばいよ。でも
I want to hear all of them! That's right. All of them are super good songs, every single one. It's crazy. But
一曲だけ。Only one. ね、一曲だけですから選んでくださいね。
Only one. Only one. Hey, it's just one song, so please choose.
そうだね。Pleaseお願いしま、どれがいいかな。どれがいいかな。Okay. お願いします。
That's right. Please, which one would be good? Which one would be good? Okay. Please.
わあ、楽しみ。頑張ります。ねえ。
Wow, I'm excited. I'll do my best. Yeah.
いや、カリオペ本当にね。4、4年、メジャーデビューして4年。本当に駆け抜けてきたよね。
Man, Calliope really. 4, 4 years since major debut, 4 years. You've really run through it all.
いろいろやってますよね。
You've done all sorts of things.
ね、なんかアニメのタイアップとかもね、たくさん決まって、きました。きました。ね、嬉しい。My dream。
Yeah, like anime tie-ups and stuff, a lot of them got decided. They came. They came. Yeah, I'm so happy. My dream.
ね、夢が叶えた。すごい！めっちゃ嬉しい。ありがとうございます。
Yeah, dreams came true. Amazing! I'm so happy. Thank you very much.
皆さんのおかげで、素敵な先輩のおかげでも My inspiration。Thank you so much, everybody!
Thanks to everyone, thanks to amazing senpai, and also my inspiration. Thank you so much, everybody!
Yay! Let's keep shooting for the moon. そうだよ。うん。
Yay! Let's keep shooting for the moon. That's right. Yeah.
Let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody's writing what what they want. Okay,すごい、すごい。今、好きな曲。
Let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody's writing what what they want. Okay, amazing, amazing. Now, favorite song.
おお、すごい、すごい。ね、すごい。Many many many many! おお、投票がまだ。投票だ、go! チューズ、チューズ、チューズだから選んで選んで。
Oh, amazing, amazing. Wow, amazing. Many many many many! Oh, voting is still going. Voting, go! Choose, choose, choose, so pick, pick.
選んだ？始まってる？投票もう少し長くやりますてよ。うん。
Did you pick? Has it started? Let's do the voting a bit longer. Yeah.
Okay, a little bit longer. Long, long time. Yes, please choose one. It's hard 難しいと思うけど。
Okay, a little bit longer. Long, long time. Yes, please choose one. It's hard, even though I think it's difficult.
Let's drink water. あ、確かに。水杯 in the glass。Okay.
Let's drink water. Ah, true. Water cheers in the glass. Okay.
Cheers! Cheers! Thank you, senpai.
ジャパニーズ cheersなんだと思う。うん、乾杯。
I wonder if it's Japanese cheers. Yeah, kanpai.
乾杯！最近の流行りなんていうとわ？
Kanpai! What would you call a recent trend?
チアーズ。KP、KPですね。え、たくさん使いたいと思う。
Cheers. KP, KP. Uh, I think I want to use it a lot.
使ってください。日本語でも使うから。乾杯だけ、KP、KP、KP、KP、KP。
Please use it. We use it in Japanese too. Just kanpai, KP, KP, KP, KP.
へいへい、パーティーピープルが使ってますよ。パーティーピープル、いやパーティーピープルじゃないけど使いますよ。
Hey hey, party people are using it. Party people, well not party people, but we use it.
Party people in the house, let's go! はい。
Party people in the house, let's go! Yes.
いいですね。ナイス。
Sounds good. Nice.
Alright, is the voting closed? どうかな、どうかな。決まったかな、決まったかな。決まったかな、ちょっとわかんないな。
Alright, is the voting closed? I wonder, I wonder. Has it been decided? Has it been decided? Has it been decided? I'm not quite sure.
皆さん、お水美味しいだって。美味しい？美味しい？
Everyone says the water is delicious. Delicious? Delicious?
Okay.
Oh, close?
あ、不安もここ、不安もここ見てくれてる？Thanks for coming.
Ah, are you looking here too? Thanks for coming.
I love...
フッ、もう...
Heh, already...
え、Thank you, thank you.
Eh, thank you, thank you.
あ、今からスタート？
Ah, starting now?
今からスタート。
Starting now.
オッケー、今からスタート。オッケー、ノープラブル。
Okay, starting now. Okay, no problem.
Push, push, go go go, push, please.
ちなみに、カリオペの他の知らせがあるんだけど、あの、カバー曲もリリースします。
By the way, Calliope has another announcement—um, I'm also releasing a cover song.
Yes, check it out! The cover song is "In My Head" by Natori. Check it out, In My Head.
I like song. You like it? Yeah, In My Head.
I like songs. You like it? Yeah, "In My Head."
In my head. Yeah, please listen to it, Keitha-san is in it.
"In My Head." Yeah, please listen to it, Keithan is in it.
そう、あのこのライブの後、そしてそのあとはメンバーズ限定。はい、デス。
Right, um, after this live stream, and after that, it's members-only. Yes, this.
We have goods. Goods are going to be released very soon, so I wanted to tell you guys about the goods.
グッズもありますので、リミテッド、リミテッドもありますので、ちゃんと伝えたかったけど、最後のほう、配信の最後のほうは深夜に流しますが。
There are goods as well, and there are limited edition ones too, so I wanted to make sure I told you, though near the end—the very end of the stream—we'll stream it late at night.
But in about 2 minutes, 本当にもうすぐ、あのそのURL出るから、のそのURL準備しといて、そうですね、準備して。心も準備して。
But in about 2 minutes, really very soon, that URL is coming out, so get that URL ready, yeah, get ready. Get your hearts ready too.
Yes, okay.
Oh, check it out! Here they are! Yes, カッコイイ！
Oh, check it out! Here they are! Yes, so cool!
Dark fantasy, カリオペ、Dark fantasy theme, Thank you. I'm so cool, I'm like, すごい！
Dark fantasy, Calliope, dark fantasy theme. Thank you. I'm so cool, I'm like, amazing!
Dark fantasy game boss. あの、魔王みたい。Yes, 魔王 is English, 何?
A dark fantasy game boss. Um, like a Demon King. Yes, "Demon King" in English is... what?
魔王, uh, like, um, なんて言えばいいかな。Dark, Dark, Dark King? Dark King! Yes! Dark King! えご、魔王、よかったね。
Demon King, uh, like, um, how should I put it. Dark, Dark, Dark King? Dark King! Yes! Dark King! Heh, Demon King, that's nice.
あ、豊洲収容 by the way.
Ah, Toyosu Pit too, by the way.
Voting is over. It's done. Yay! Thank you so much. Oh my god, I'm excited to see what you guys chose.
Now then, we should sing one more song then, shouldn't we? Cuz, but look out for the goods.
Goods URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch. チェックしてね、グッズ買って。
Goods URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch. Check it out, buy the goods.
よろしくね。オッケイ。そ、あの、たくさん休みましたね、だから。Let's sing one more song! Yeah! もう1曲一緒に歌いたいと思います。いいですか、みなさん。いいですか。オッケイ。
Please look forward to it. Okay. So, um, we took a lot of rest, so. Let's sing one more song! Yeah! We'd like to sing one more song together. Is that alright, everyone? Is that alright? Okay.
うん、じゃあ二人ならやれるさ。やれるさ。Next song is,
Yeah, well, if it's the two of us, we can do it. We can do it. Next song is...
GOLD UNBALANCE!
確かな物語に価値を置く相槌
Nodding in approval, placing value on a certain story
戯れ言と手を交わし眼を替えろ
Exchanging words of idle talk, changing our eyes
焦げた胸をささげ、Cheers!
Offering up a scorched chest, cheers!
感情のフィクションで綺麗をアイラブ
Loving the beauty created by emotional fiction
一瞬の戸惑いが最後の衝動
A fleeting hesitation is our final impulse
失敗を成果も味わえ Wherever we go 黄金マジック
Savoring both failure and achievement, wherever we go, golden magic
君になんてないよ、世界で偶然を重ねた光
There's nothing like you—a light stacking coincidences in this world
描く孤独誰にもなれない、言葉を紡いでよ
Painting a solitude nobody else can become, spin your words
なめくじゃないよ、小さな勇気一足じゃ自分
Don't underestimate it, a single step of small courage isn't enough for yourself
強気に掴みへと、あとは二人ならやれる
To boldly grasp the future, after all, if it's the two of us, we can do it
Let's out
泥水と澄み切って墓荒らす、ウザいウザいクライ
Murky water and crystal clarity, grave-robbing, annoying, annoying, crying
ドヨメク夜の跡は無限に、Reflect 満ちて尽きない
The aftermath of the swirling night is infinite, reflect, fill and never end
羨望の道は此の物狂おそ、世代にも笑われはしざ
This mad path of envy, even generations won't laugh at it
差異の重労働の中でしょうがない、無茶苦茶に捨てよ
In the heavy labor of differences, it can't be helped, throwing it away recklessly
初めての習うやれる覚悟を、敗者と勝者の綴れ
Learning for the first time the resolve to do it, the tapestry of losers and winners
弾け出されたホジボリのくず
The hollowed-out scraps bursting forth
見晴らし上々に、黒の残しは消せない二人ならやれる
With a superb view, we can't erase what black leaves behind, if it's the two of us we can do it
Let's out 粋がる度の一笑ったもん勝ちかすんなもん
Let's out, laughing at every bravado, winner takes all, don't mind it
握れレッドバスター、もはやいられない
Grasp the red buzzer, we can no longer stay
エンタメライダ、主客きゃ客はキリクキ、絶望も栄誉も連れ去れ、ファイバック
Entertainer, host and guest, whisk away despair and honor, fly back
どんな時でも変わらないんだって
No matter what time it is, it never changes
歪まれた現実に囚われて、This life style is shocking chances
Trapped in a distorted reality, this lifestyle is shocking chances
あきあきしてんだろ
You're sick of it, aren't you?
Living in a world with no direction, reach out with the lights, do we make a connection?
Tearing the worlds apart, facing it up, side by side, once again, it's us against the world
不確かなお話に
In this uncertain story,
勝ち取るはアイデンティティ
what we want to win is our identity.
あれやこれやと手を替え品を替え
Trying this and that, changing means and methods,
ドキリと胸を刺す激情
a passion that stabs the chest suddenly.
感情はノンフィクションで喜怒哀楽
Emotions are non-fiction, joy, anger, sorrow,
一心同体 一切合切の衝動
one body and soul, every single impulse.
失敗も成功も味わえ
Taste both failure and success,
我らゴールデンバディ
we are the golden buddy.
意味なんてないような世界で
In a world that seems to have no meaning,
偶然を重ねた光
a light formed by overlapping coincidences.
脈打つ鼓動
A pulsating heartbeat,
誰にもなれない言葉を紡いで
weave words that no one else can become.
舐めんなじぇーよ
Don't underestimate me,
小さな勇気一つありゃ十分
just one bit of small courage is enough,
気高に高みへと 圧倒絶頂
proudly toward the heights, overwhelming pinnacle,
2人ならやれるさ
if we're together, we can do it.
back-to-back, no matter what
背負ったもん武器に変わるspot
the spot where what we've carried turns into a weapon.
段違い遠くまで飛ばすshout
A different level, a shout that flies far away,
誰も邪魔できねえこのroutex
no one can disturb this route.
1等2等3等通って
Talking about 1st, 2nd, 3rd options,
はなからloser 欲求不満のハート
you're a loser from the start...
What's up, you crazy skeleton?
What's up, you crazy skeletons?
I mean,
dearest deadbeats, the hour is finally upon us.
The sale of Mori Calliope's birthday celebration goods is about to begin.
On this most auspicious day, you've been granted a great blessing by death herself.
A most fortunate occurrence for thee, that such a glorious chest should appear before thy eyes.
Let's take a peek at what the goddess of death herself has to offer, shall we?
Firstly, wouldst thou find comfort in dear Death's embrace?
If it be so, take some warmth along thy journey with this very large, rollable blanket featuring a most intimidating and battle-ready maiden,
If it be so, take some warmth along thy journey with this very large, rollable blanket
yours truly, designed by my favorite dark fantasy artist, Shimhaq!
featuring a most intimidating and battle-ready maiden, yours truly,
Woo!
designed by my favorite dark fantasy artist, Shimhaq! Woo!
The maiden in question possesses artworks en masse from this particular individual, so I'd be most elated if you bought it for yourself.
Lay it across your bed, hang it on your wall, take it with you on an outing—think of the possibilities!
Secondly, whilst on thy noble journey, thou mayest come to need a spark of aid.
If it be so, take one of these amulets: the emblem of a knight to boost your strength, the emblem of a samurai to grant you additional dexterity,
the emblem of a priestess to bestow additional health to thy weary body, and lastly,
the emblem of a necromancer to grant the additional intelligence.
Alas, as fortune be a fickle mistress, thou may only receive one in a set. I pray thee be granted the boon most favorable to thy quest.
Or... or you could just purchase them all separately if you're looking to speedrun the experience, I suppose.
Or you could just purchase them all separately if you're looking to speedrun the experience, I suppose.
Thirdly, I present to thee the shining centerpiece of this valuable collection.
Take a moment of repose and sit beside this warm and healing light, granted unto thee by Death herself.
A lantern to revive thee as many times as needed throughout even the most daunting of journeys, may it light thy way to victory or to sweet dreams, whichever is preferred.
Enjoy an elegant design chosen specifically by myself. And of course, how could one continue a journey into vast and unforgiving lands without a source of healing?
Rejuvenate thyself with this generous flask, or rather, glass, that seems to refill endlessly upon rest at your lantern—at least, I think it will.
There really are no guarantees in this life, but give it a try yourself, see if the myths are true. Enjoy your favorite beverage during a night of exploring your favorite fantasy scenarios.
But naturally, it'd do me no good to leave you without the... I don't know, bedtime story?
But naturally, it'd do me no good to leave you without a... I don't know, bedtime story?
To put this enchanting collection into context, so please enjoy a short audiobook-style recording of a fantastical story written by yours truly.
Believe it or not, we are the stars of this tale, so enjoy it on a rainy evening wrapped warmly in Death's embrace.
The... the blanket, I mean. You can use the flask, uh, also for like drinking at the same time. I don't know, just you should really buy the full set.
And definitely do, because lucky skeletons who act fast and purchase the entire set will be granted a hand-signed postcard with a special color variant of Shimhaq's masterpiece rendition of Death herself.
Happy Birthday to me!!
6 birthdays, huh?! This time was even more special than usual.
Much love to my guests, my Dead Beats, my band,
and everyone who wants to see me fly!
Let's have an even happier year... together!!
Calliope Mori